Guide to the Jim Dow photographs, 1966-2019 RL.11709
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Negatives, 1966-2018; Original identifiers generally consist of the year taken and a two-digit number; after the 1970s the photographer's initials (jdd) preface all identifiers but are not expressed in this inventory. A few of the earliest identifiers may not always include the year, but others ha
  - Jobs and Commissions, 2004; 1 folder (Box 41)
    Aquarium train stop platform, Boston, MA. Color.
  - Jobs and Commissions, 2005; 1 folder (Box 41)
  - Jobs and Commissions, 2005; 2 folders (Box 41)
    Legacy identifiers: 2007-105 to 2007-155
    Tufts University, MA. Various locations. Color.
  - Jobs and Commissions, 2007; 2 folders (Box 41)
    Legacy identifiers: 2007-69 to 2007-105; 2007-193 to 2007-219; some with no identifiers
    Brown University, Providence, RI; Phillips Academy, Andover, MA. Various locations. Color.
  - Jobs and Commissions, 2008; 3 folders (Box 41)
    Legacy identifiers: 2008-01 to 2008-12; 2008-52 to 2008-97; 2008-155 to 2008-165
    Phillips Academy, Andover, MA; Vassar College; Poughkeepsie, NY. Various locations. Color.
- Photography and Art History teaching slides, approximately 1990s-2010s; 78 linear ft. 77 boxes (Oversize-box 42-117)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Color and black-and-white film transparencies (mounted slides)
  Series consists of a large archive of approximately 120,960 color and black-and-white slides used by photographer Jim Dow to teach courses on photography and art history, chiefly at Harvard, Tufts, and the School of the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston. Some may also document exhibit installations or other programs and collections. The slide transparencies are housed in slide boxes within 76 larger flat boxes; each box is estimated to hold approximately 2160 slides.
  Contents of the series as currently known include:
  -Slides used in History of Photography courses: 62 boxes (16.5 x 18.5 x 3 inches). Organized by artist/photographer or topic and includes a large set of slides with images relating to the history of photographic processes.
  -Slides used in Contemporary Art History courses: 12 boxes, (16.5 x 18.5 x 3 inches)
  -Slides used in Contemporary Art History courses: 1 box, nonstandard size
  -Slides of Jim Dow's own work, 1 small box marked JDD
  -Canadian Center for Architecture slides and albums/catalogs: 1 box
  Access restricted. Collection is in process and is currently closed to use as of 10/2020.
- Teaching Files (electronic format), approximately 1990s-2010s; 10 Terabytes 2 hard drives (Box 118)
  Materials are currently in process and are closed to use. Please contact the Rubenstein Library for more details.
  These electronic files are related to Jim Dow's courses on the history of photography and contemporary art. Contents may include syllabi, notes, lectures, and bibliographies. Dates are approximate. Student work is not included.